You said you'd marry Joey?
你答應要嫁給喬伊？
Okay, you have to realize, I was exhausted, I was emotional.
你要知道我可是累壞了 當時我很情緒化
I would have said yes to anybody.
任何人求婚，我都會答應的
Like that time when you and I got married.
就像上次你向我求婚一樣
I'm not helping.
我轉不過來了
So you said yes to him, and you just had our baby?
你才剛生下我們的小孩 卻答應要嫁給他？
That is right. And traditionally, the daddy gives the mommy a present.
沒錯，而且按照習俗 父親應該要送母親一個禮物的
But I am prepared to let that go.
但是我不打算跟你計較
So when I came here to see if you wanted to maybe start things up again..
所以當我過來看你 是否願意重新來過…
you were engaged to my best friend?
你已經跟我最要好的朋友訂婚了？
Well..
嗯…
Really?
真的嗎？
I thought Chandler was your best friend.
我以為錢德才是你最要好的朋友
Well, Chandler's my oldest friend. Joey's my.. No!
錢德是我的老朋友 喬伊是我…不！
Hey, I'm gonna take off. I just wanted to say goodbye.
嘿，我要走了 進來說一聲再見
Rachel said she'd marry you?
瑞秋答應要嫁給你？
This isn't the right room. Sorry, folks.
我走錯房間了，不好意思
The One Where Emma Cries
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
I don't want to be negative. So I'll say most of the signs you bought are good.
我不想太機車，所以我要說 你挑的標語大部分都是很棒的
No, they ran out of "It's a Girl!" But I can fix this one.
「我是女生！」賣完了 但是我可以處理一下的
（我不是男生！）
See? Huh?
瞧？怎樣？
So sexy.
真性感
- Honey? - Yeah?
-親愛的？ -什麼？
- Honey, why don't you lie down? - It's okay.
-親愛的，你何不去躺下休息呢？ -沒關係
Ross and Rachel will be back soon, and then I gotta go to the office.
羅斯跟瑞秋很快就要回來了 然後我得要進辦公室
Am I producing them?
這是從我嘴裡長的嗎？
- Why are you so tired? - I couldn't sleep last night.
-你為什麼這樣累呢？ -我昨晚無法入睡
I started worrying about this big divisional meeting I have today.
我很擔心今天的大型部門會議
The more I worried, the more I couldn't sleep.
我越是擔心 越是沒有辦法入睡
You know, and then I was, like, "If I fall asleep now, I'll get six hours' sleep.
你知道的，我會想 如果現在睡著，我頂多睡六小時
But if I fall asleep now, I'll get five hours' sleep."
但是如果我現在睡著 我頂多睡五個小時
No matter what I did, I couldn't fall asleep.
無論我怎麼試，就是睡不著
You know what you should've done? Told yourself that little story.
你知道你應該做什麼嗎？
對你自己講那個小故事
- Hi. - Hey.
-嗨 -嘿
- Welcome home. - Hi.
-歡迎回家 -嗨
Phoebe did the signs.
標示是菲比做的
You guys, thanks for doing this.
你們，真是太謝謝你們了
Look at all that stuff people sent.
瞧瞧大家送來的禮物
Oh, my gosh. Look, there's something every mother needs.
喔，我的天啊 這正是每個母親所需要的
A giant, stuffed gorilla that takes up the entire apartment.
一個擠爆整間公寓的大型黑猩猩娃娃
What are people think..? You guys, I love it.
真搞不懂有些人在想…？ 你們大家，我真是太喜歡了
Hey, so where's Ross?
嘿，羅斯在哪呢？
He's downstairs getting the stuff out of the cab.
他在樓下把東西搬出計程車
- Is he still mad at us? - Well, you more than me.
-他還在氣我們兩個嗎？ -氣你多過於我
But he can't stay too mad at me. I mean, I just had his baby.
他總不能一直跟我生氣 我才剛生下他的小孩耶
That's not fair. I can't do that.
太不公平了，我又不會生
I'm not sure you should be here when he comes up.
我不知道他上來時 你應不應該在場
I didn't think I should be here either. But somebody said he'd be over it.
我也不認為我該在場 但有人跟我說羅斯應該已經釋懷了
Hey, what do I know? I wanted to get a bigger gorilla.
嘿，我怎麼會知道呢？ 我只是想要買大只一點的黑猩猩啊
The numbers we're seeing in Chicago, New York and London are solid.
我們在芝加哥、紐約 與倫敦的業績都很扎實
But many of our field offices have reported disappointing yields.
但是我們許多分公司已經呈報衰退
Boston is down. Atlanta is down. Houston is down.
波士頓衰退、亞特蘭大衰退 休士頓衰退
I could go on and on. But instead of boring you..
我可以一直念下去 但是為了不要讓你們覺得無趣
I'll go straight to my 42-point plan.
我直接說明我的四十二點計劃好了
Walter.
華特
She's just so cute.
她真是太可愛了
I just want to bite her ear off and use it as a sucking candy.
我真想咬下她的耳朵 當成糖果一樣吸
Phoebe.
菲比
But I could take one of those little feet and put it in a pita pocket.
但是我可以把這些小腳 放到麵餅裡面
- Okay. I put most of the stuff away. - Oh, great. The pacifiers?
-好了，我把大部分的東西都放好了 -喔，太好了，奶嘴呢？
- It's in the cupboard. - The burping cloths?
-在櫃櫥裡 -打嗝圍兜？
- Linen closet. - The diapers?
-毛巾櫥裡 -尿布？
In the hospital.
在醫院
- Wow, you guys got a hospital? Fancy. - No, I left the diapers at the hospital.
-哇，你們有間醫院？真酷 -不，我把尿布忘在醫院了
There's some in the bag, but I'll run out and get some more.
在袋子裡面還有一些 但是我現在就出去多買一些
All right, thanks.
好的，謝謝
Could you stop at the coffeehouse and get me a muffin?
經過咖啡屋時可以幫我買個鬆餅嗎？
- Sure. What kind? - Let me think.
-當然，什麼口味的？ -讓我想想
What do I want?
我要什麼口味呢？
Please, take your time. It's an important decision, not like..
請你慢慢想 這是非常重要的決定，不像是…
say, I don't know, deciding to marry someone. This is about a muffin.
決定要嫁給誰那樣簡單 這是鬆餅喔
- Blueberry. - Blueberry it is.
-藍莓的 -好吧，藍莓
Thank you.
謝謝你
Wow, he's not letting this go, is he?
哇，他還在記恨，對吧？
God, how long do you think that's gonna last?
天啊，你覺得這會持續多久呢？
I don't know. He got over the "We were on a break" thing quickly.
我不知道，他倒是對「暫時分手一下」 那件事，釋懷的挺快的
You know what, I can't worry about it right now.
你們知道嗎？ 我現在無法去擔心那件事
Because I've got the cutie little baby.
因為我有了這個可愛的小寶貝
I can't believe how much I love her. I mean, I can't get enough of her.
我無法相信我是這樣的愛她 我是說，我太愛她了
Like, right now? I miss her. I actually miss her.
就像現在，我好想她 我真的好想她
You know, that's her?
你知道嗎？她就在這裡
I know. I know, but she's sleeping.
我知道，但是她在睡覺
It's not like when she's awake and I can see her stretch and wiggle.
如果她醒著，我就可以看她扭來扭去的
Oh, my God, have you seen her yawn?
喔，天啊，看到她打哈欠沒？
- It's so cute. - I know.
-真是太可愛了 -真的是
When do you think she's gonna wake up?
你們覺得她什麼時候會醒來？
She told me to ring her if she's not up by 11.
她告訴我，如果她十一點還沒醒 要我打電話給她
She has a job interview.
她有個面試要去
Okay, but the clouds part when she yawns.
好的，但是當她打哈欠時 烏雲都消散了
God, look at her sleeping. I love her so much.
天啊，瞧她睡著的樣子 我好愛她
- I think I'm gonna wake her up. - Rach, no.
-我想我要把她吵醒 -瑞秋，不要
You know, you're never supposed to wake a sleeping baby.
你永遠都不應該吵醒熟睡的嬰兒
Well, I can do whatever I want. I made her.
我可以高興怎樣做就怎樣做 她是我生的
Come on, little girl. Yes. Hello, Emma. Hello. Hi.
來吧，小女孩 是的，哈囉，艾□，哈囉，嗨
Well, I would say I told you so, but she's kind of doing that for me.
我應該說我早就告訴過你了 但是她已經幫我說了
I'm sorry. Mommy's so sorry. Go back to sleep.
我很抱歉，媽咪很抱歉 再睡吧
Go back to sleep.
再睡覺吧
- It breaks your heart, doesn't it? - It really does.
-這真是令人心疼，不是嗎？ -沒錯
How long do you think we have to stay?
你認為我們還要呆多久？
Okay, if everyone's onboard, it's settled.
好了，如果每個人都各就各位 那就搞定了
Chandler?
錢德？
- Chandler? - Yeah.
-錢德？ -怎樣
Are you onboard?
你要就位了嗎？
Yes.
是的
Well, then problem solved. Chandler will run our office in Tulsa.
那麼問題就解決了 錢德會負責我們在土爾沙的辦公室
You're gonna love Oklahoma.
你會喜歡奧克拉荷馬的
All right. We already tried feeding her, changing her, burping her..
好了，我們已經餵過她了 換過尿布、幫她打嗝了…
Try this one. "Go back in time and listen to Phoebe."
試試看這個 回去聽聽菲比的話吧
- All right, here's something. - What?
-好了，試試看這個 -什麼？
It says to try holding the baby close to your body..
這裡說試著把嬰兒抱起，貼近身體…
and then swing her rapidly from side to side.
然後快速的左右搖
Okay.
好的
It worked!
太有效了！
No. Just stopped to throw up a little bit.
不，只是讓她吐了一點奶
Mon, what am I gonna do?
摩妮卡，我應該怎麼辦呢？
It's been hours, and it won't stop crying.
已經好幾個小時了 它就是哭個不停
- She, Rach. Not it. She. - Yeah. I'm not so sure.
-她，瑞秋，不是它，是她 -是喔，我可不太確定了
- Oh, my God, I'm losing my mind. - Yeah, no kidding.
-喔，我的天啊，我快瘋了 -是啊，說得沒錯
All right, this just proves no good can come from having sex with Ross!
這正好證明跟羅斯做愛 絕對沒有好事會發生
Hey, Gunther. Can I get a couple of blueberry muffins to go?
嘿，阿甘，我要外帶幾個藍莓鬆餅
- Diapers, huh? - Yep.
-尿布，是吧？ -是的
So I guess Rachel had your baby?
我猜瑞秋生下你的小孩了
- Yep. Can you believe it? - Nope.
-是啊，你能相信嗎？ -不能
I can't even believe she slept with you in the first place.
首先我就不能相信 她竟然會跟你上床
You mean, like..
你是說，像是…
Hey.
嘿
I know you're pissed at me, but we have to talk about this.
我知道你生我的氣 但是我們必須談一談
Actually, we don't.
事實上我們不需要
Fine. Okay. But I gotta say, technically, I didn't even do anything wrong.
隨便，但是我要說 技術上而言，我並沒有做錯什麼
What? You didn't do anything wrong?
什麼？你並沒有做錯什麼？
- I said I didn't technically. - Okay.
-我說是技術上而言 -好的
Let's put aside the fact that you "accidentally"..
我們暫時不管你「不小心」…
picked up my grandmother's ring and you "accidentally" proposed to Rachel.
撿起我祖母的戒指，然後又 「不小心」跟瑞秋求婚
Can I just stop you there for a second?
我可以先打斷你一下嗎？
When people do this:
當有人做這個動作時…
I don't really know what that means.
我真的不知道是什麼意思
You were saying?
你剛剛說什麼？
And I could even understand that you couldn't tell Rachel.
我還可以諒解你沒有跟瑞秋解釋
But why couldn't you tell me? You had all day to, and you didn't.
但是為什麼你沒有告訴我呢？ 你有一整天可以說，你卻沒有
I know. I should've. "I'm sorry."
我知道，我應該說「我很抱歉」
Not using it right, Joe.
你用錯地方了，喬伊
"I'm sorry."
「我很抱歉」
- I'm gonna go. - No, come on.
-我要走了 -不，別這樣
- Ross, we have to get past this. - Give me the bag.
-羅斯，我們必須要放下這件事 -把袋子給我
No, I don't know what else to do. I said I'm sorry, now..
不，我不知道還能怎樣 我已經道歉了，現在…
Now you should scream at me or curse me or hit me.
現在你應該對我吼叫、咒罵 或是打我
- I'm not gonna hit you. - You'll feel better. I'll feel better.
-我不會打你的 -你會比較好過，我也會比較好過
You know you want to, I can see it in your eyes.
你知道，你想打我 我從你眼中看得出來
- I don't. - A little bit.
-我不想 -有一點
- No. - Little bit.
-不想 -有一點
- No. - A little bit more.
-不想 -多一點了
- Give me the bag. Give me the bag. - No, hit me. Hit me.
-把那個袋子給我，把袋子給我 -不，打我，打我
- Give me the bag. I'm not kidding. - Hit me.
-給我袋子，給我袋子 -打我
- No. - Hit me. Hit me. Hit me!
-不 -打我，打我，打我！
- You ducked! - I'm sorry! It was a reflex!
-你閃開了！ -我很抱歉！這是反射動作！
- Oh, my God! This really hurts! - I couldn't help it.
-喔，天啊！真的好痛！ -我不得不閃哪！
When a fist comes at your face, you duck. Look.
當有拳頭要打上你的臉 你會閃啊，瞧
What is the matter with you?
你是怎麼搞的？
You were supposed to duck! Why didn't you?
你應該要閃的！為什麼沒閃呢？
Let's talk on the way to the hospital.
我們去醫院的路上再談
Good. Yeah, maybe while we're there, they can check your reflexes.
好，是啊，或許當我們過去的時候 他們可以檢查一下你的反射神經
- Try feeding her again. - I already fed her.
-再餵她看看 -我已經餵過了
I know. That's why I said, "Again!"
我知道，所以我說「再」
You guys, we can't turn on each other, okay?
你們，我們不可以窩裡反，好嗎？
That's just what she wants.
這正是她想要的
- Hi. - Hey.
-嗨 -嘿
I told you you shouldn't have let her watch Terms of Endearment.
我告訴過你別讓她看《親情關係》
- Can I talk to you outside? - Just stay here.
-我們可以到外面談談嗎？ -待在這裡
I'm gonna check her diaper. Phoebe, you want to come?
我要去檢查她的尿布 菲比，你要不要一起來呢？
I'm kind of part of this.
這事與我也有關
Actually, it's a husband-and-wife kind of thing.
事實上，這是夫妻兩人之間的事
I knew I should've married Chandler.
我就知道我應該嫁給錢德的
- Okay, what's up? - Okay.
-好了，怎麼回事呢？ -好的
You know we said it would be fun to move to Paris for a year?
我們曾經討論過如果能搬到巴黎 住一年一定會很棒
And you could study French cooking, and I could write..
你可以學習法式烹飪 我可以寫作…
and we could picnic along the Seine, and go wine-tasting in Bordeaux.
我們可以在塞納河畔野餐 去波爾多品酒
- Yeah. - Okay.
-是啊 -很好
You know how people say that Tulsa..
你知道有些人說土爾沙…
is the Paris of Oklahoma?
就像是奧克拉荷馬州的巴黎嗎？
What? Who says that?
什麼？是誰說的？
People who have never been to Paris?
那些從沒去過巴黎的人說的
- Well, what's going on? - We're moving to Tulsa.
-到底是怎麼回事？ -我們要搬去土爾沙了
- Excuse me? - Okay.
-你說什麼？ -好吧
Ms. McKenna, she kind of works above my boss.
我老闆的上司，麥肯納小姐
- I think you actually met her. - Don't care. Get back to Tulsa.
-我想你應該見過她 -我不在乎，快說土爾沙是怎麼回事
She asked me to move to Tulsa and be president of our office there.
她要我搬到土爾沙 去當那邊分公司的總經理
And I was sleeping and apparently said yes.
我當時正在打瞌睡，然後 顯然我是答應她了
- Tulsa, Oklahoma? - The Sooner State.
-奧克拉荷馬州的土爾沙？ -早到者之州
Whatever that is.
不管那是什麼東東
Chandler, I don't even want to see the musical Oklahoma.
錢德，我連歌舞劇《奧克拉荷馬》 都不想看
"Oh, What a Beautiful Morning, " "Surrey With the Fringe on Top"?
「喔，美妙的早晨」 「坐在馬車上頭」（奧劇內容）
Are you trying to tell me we're moving to Oklahoma or that you're gay?
你是在說我們要搬去奧克拉荷馬 還是說你是同性戀？
I don't think I can get out of this.
我想我可能躲不掉了
- Oh, my God! - But you don't know..
-喔，天啊！ -但是你不知道…
it could be like Paris. You can still take a cooking class..
土爾沙可能會像巴黎一樣 你還是可以在當地的大學…
at Oral Roberts University.
上烹飪課
All right, not that this matters, but did they at least offer you a huge raise?
好吧，這些都沒關係 但至少他們有幫你加薪吧？
No. But they are going to lease us a Ford Focus.
沒有，但是他們會 幫我們租一台福特小車
- I'll get out of it. - Thank you.
-我會試著脫身 -謝謝
- What is wrong with Emma? - She misunderstood.
-艾□是怎麼了？ -她誤會了
She thought she was moving to Tulsa.
她以為是她要搬到土爾沙
Ma'am, do you have a minute?
請問您現在有空嗎？
I kind of have some bad news. I don't think I can move to Tulsa.
我有些壞消息 我想我不能去土爾沙了
- What? - It's a funny story, actually.
-什麼？ -事實上這是件很好笑的事
I kind of fell asleep in the meeting this morning.
我在今天早上的會議上睡著了
So when I said I'd move to Tulsa, I didn't really know what I was saying.
所以當我說我可以搬到土爾沙時 我根本不知道我在說什麼
You fell asleep?
你睡著了？
But only because I was up all night worried about this meeting.
但那是因為我整晚為會議擔心而失眠
Isn't that funny?
是不是很好笑呢？
Irony. Not a fan? All right.
很諷刺，不好笑？好吧
See, here's the thing.
好吧，事情是這樣的
I went home and told my wife about Tulsa, and she won't go.
我回家告訴我老婆土爾沙的事 但是她不想去
See me, I love Tulsa. Tulsa is heaven. Tulsa is ltaly.
至於我，我愛死土爾沙了 土爾沙是天堂，土爾沙是意大利
Please don't make me go there.
拜託別逼我搬去那裡
- Chandler, I.. - I know that you're upset..
-錢德，我… -我知道你很不高興…
but I just.. I would really rather just stay here.
但是我只是… 我真的寧可留在這裡
Not here in your office..
不是說在你的辦公室這裡…
here at the company..
而是在這裡的這間公司
where I'm rapidly feeling unwelcome.
我在這裡超有歸屬感的
No, look, Carol. Can I call you Carol?
聽著，凱蘿 我可以叫你凱蘿嗎？
Why would I when your name is Elaine?
我真不應該 因為你的名字是依蓮
What a great picture of your son. Strapping.
你兒子拍得真棒，雄壯威武
That's a picture of your daughter, isn't it?
是你女兒的照片，對吧？
Well, she's lovely. I like a girl with a strong jaw.
她真是甜美 我喜歡有堅毅下巴的女孩
I'll call you from Tulsa.
我會從土爾沙打電話給你的
Hey. So how is it?
嘿，怎樣呢？
- I broke my thumb. - Your thumb?
-我的拇指斷了 -你的拇指？
That's weird. Are you sure you're punching right?
真是奇怪，你確定 你出拳的方式是正確的嗎？
Make a fist.
握拳
Maybe later.
或許等一下好了
Ross, I feel terrible.
羅斯，我覺得很糟糕
You know what, you can go. I just have to fill out some forms.
你可以走了 我只要填一些表格就可以了
You want me to help you with that?
需要我幫忙嗎？
Why, does it look like I'm having trouble with my misshapen claw?
為什麼？我看起來像是沒辦法 使用我的畸形爪子嗎？
Name?
姓名？
No, I know Ross. But what's it short for?
我知道羅斯 但是那是什麼的簡稱呢？
You know, like Rossell.
你知道的，像是羅素
Or Rosstrophor.
或是羅斯多福
Just Ross.
就是羅斯
It's pretty.
好名字
- Okay, date of birth? - You know my birthday.
-好了，生日呢？ -你知道我生日的
Sure.
當然
May.. tember?
五…九月？
- October 18. - Occupation? Dinosaurs.
-十月十八日 -職業？恐龍
Actually, I'm a paleon.. Dinosaurs is fine.
事實上我是古生物… 恐龍也可以啦
The drawing is not.
圖畫的並不是
All right, who do you want as your emergency contact?
好了，緊急聯絡人是誰呢？
- Rachel, I guess. - Okay. Relationship?
-瑞秋，我想應該是吧 -好的，關係呢？
Boy, this could take a while.
天啊，這可能要花上一點時間
- Just put roommate. - Come on.
-寫室友 -少來了
You guys are more than that. You're gonna get together, right?
你們比室友還更進一步 你們要在一起了，不是嗎？
I don't think that we are.
我不認為我們有要在一起
But you two are supposed to be together.
但是你們應該要在一起的
Well, I thought so too. But then she said she'd marry you.
我也這樣想過 但是她卻答應要嫁給你
Come on, Ross, that didn't mean anything.
別這樣，羅斯 那根本沒有什麼
She'd just had the baby. She was freaked out about doing it alone.
她才剛生產完嚇壞了 要獨自扛起一切
- She would have said yes to anybody. - Yeah, that's what she said.
-任何人求婚，她都會答應的 -是啊，她也是這樣說
- So? - So I don't want to be just anybody.
-所以呢？ -所以我不想要當任何人
- Wow. - You know what?
-哇 -你知道嗎？
It's better this way anyway.
反正這樣也比較好
I don't know what I was thinking, going down that road again with us.
我不知道我在想什麼 再回到之前的關係
It's just much easier if we're just friends who have a kid.
如果我們純粹做朋友，只是有個小孩 那事情就會簡單多了
- Really? - Yeah.
-真的嗎？ -是啊
- And you're okay with that? - Yes. That's what we always planned.
-你這樣沒關係嗎？ -是啊，這本來就是我們的計劃
And if you have a plan, you should stick to it.
如果你有計劃，你就應該照計劃執行
That's why they call them plans. Hello?
這就是計劃的意義，不是嗎？
I'm fine.
我沒事的
Hey, for what it's worth..
嘿，關於瑞秋…
with Rachel, I don't think you'll ever be just "anybody."
我不認為你會只是「任何人」而已
Hey, there you go.
嘿，你做對了
"Thanks."
「謝謝」
Oh, my God. How long has she been crying?
喔，天啊，她哭多久了？
About a week and a half.
大約一個半星期
Well, it looks like you guys got it under control, so I'm just gonna go.
看起來你們都已經處理好了 所以我先回去了
No? Really? Misery really does love company?
不好嗎？真的？ 一定要有人共享悲慘命運嗎？
All right.
好吧
- Try holding her a different way. - Look, I'm doing the best I can.
-試著用另一種方式抱她 -我已經盡力而為了
- Anyone else is welcome to try. - All right, I'll try. Fine.
-任何人都歡迎來試試看 -好吧，我來試試看
- Yes. Okay. Okay. - Here you go.
-好了，好的，好的 -抱去吧
Hey. Oh, gosh.
嘿，喔，天啊
Nothing works with this child!
這小孩什麼都沒用！
God, what am I gonna do, you guys? I can't even comfort my own baby.
天啊，我該怎麼辦呢？ 我根本照顧不了我自己的孩子
- I'm the worst mother ever. - No, you're just new at this.
-我是史上最糟的母親 -不，你只不過是不熟悉罷了
You'll get better. Think about your first day at work.
你會克服的 想想你第一天上班的時候
That couldn't have been easy, but you figured that out.
那也不是很簡單的事 但你也擺平了啊
Yeah, I don't think dressing provocatively is going to help me here!
是啊，我不認為穿得辣一點 對現在的情況會有幫助！
- God, just please take her. - Okay, I'll take her. Come on.
-天啊，請幫我抱一下 -好，我來抱，來吧
Oh, boy, I have to go to the bathroom.
喔，天啊，我要去上一下廁所
I have to go scream into a pillow.
我要去枕頭堆裡吼一吼
Bouncy. Bouncy baby. Bouncy baby.
活潑，活潑的寶貝，活潑的寶貝
Oh, baby, baby. Oh, baby, baby.
喔，寶貝，寶貝，喔，寶貝，寶貝
Oh, baby, baby, baby.
喔，寶貝，寶貝，寶貝
Have I gone deaf?
我聾了嗎？
It worked. Oh, baby, baby, baby. Oh, baby, baby, baby.
有效了，喔，寶貝，寶貝，寶貝 喔，寶貝，寶貝，寶貝
You must be a fireball in bed!
你在床上一定像個火球！
I can't believe it. She's asleep. I got her to go to sleep.
我不敢相信，她睡著了 我讓她睡著了
I have actual magical powers.
我真的有神奇的魔力
I can hear traffic and birds.
我可以聽到汽車跟鳥叫聲
I can hear the voices in my head again.
我又再度聽到我腦海中的聲音了
I'm kidding.
開玩笑的
Oh, my God! You got her to stop crying!
喔，我的天！ 你讓她不再哭了！
Yes, I did. I'm Monica, super aunt.
是的，我辦到了 我是超級姑姑摩妮卡
- You are the official baby-crier stopper. - Yes, I am.
-你是正式的嬰兒止哭專家 -是啊，我正是
- You're never leaving the apartment. - Say what?
-你永遠都不能離開這間公寓了 -什麼？
That's your new job, day or night. She starts crying, I need you here.
這是你的新工作，日夜兼顧 只要她一哭，我就需要你在這裡
- No, no, no. - Thankfully, you don't need me at all.
-不，不，不 -很慶幸，你一點都不需要我
So okay. Hey, super aunt? See you later.
那麼，嘿，超級姑姑 下次見囉
Rachel? Let's give it six to eight months.
瑞秋，我們試試看六到八個月
Okay, so listen, I'm gonna go lay down.
好的，聽著，我要去睡一下
What?
什麼？
The book says whenever she's sleeping, I should be sleeping.
書上說只要她一睡 我也應該要睡
So..
所以…
Thank you.
謝謝你
Hey.
嘿
- We just got her to go to sleep. - So there can't be any yelling?
-我們才剛讓她睡著 -所以現在不能大聲吼叫囉？
No.
沒錯
- We're moving to Tulsa. - What?
-我們要搬去土爾沙了 -什麼？
I can't.. I can't hear.
我…我聽不到
- Hey. - Hey. Where have you been?
-嘿 -嘿，你去哪了？
- What happened to you? - I had a little thing with Joey.
-發生什麼事了？ -我跟喬伊打了起來
If you think this is bad, you should see him.
如果你認為這很糟糕 你應該看看喬伊
No, Ross, this is not good.
不，羅斯，這真的很糟
We have to talk about this Joey thing. Please sit.
我們必須談談喬伊這件事，請坐下
All right, you have got to get over this Joey thing.
好了，你必須放下喬伊這件事
Okay? I never really wanted to marry Joey, okay?
好嗎？我從未真的 想要嫁給喬伊，好嗎？
Okay.
好的
You know what I really, really want?
你知道我真的很想、很想要什麼嗎？
What, Rach?
什麼？
I wanna sleep.
我想要睡覺
I wanna eat. I wanna take a shower.
我想要吃東西，我想要洗澡
I mean, before she wakes up, and we gotta do this all over again.
我是說，她醒來以後 我們又有得忙了
- Right. - I mean, because I got news for you.
-沒錯 -因為我必須告訴你
Emma: not easy.
艾□，一點都不好帶
Well, that's what I'm here for.
那正是我在這裡的用意
- You want me to get that? - No, that's really okay.
-你要我去嗎？ -不，真的沒關係
- Monica? - Got it, got it, got it, got it.
-摩妮卡？ -來了，來了，來了
I've been thinking about this. And I gotta tell you, it's not my fault.
我一直在想 而且我要告訴你，這不是我的錯
- It's a natural instinct. - What are you talking about?
-那是自然的本能 -你們在說什麼？
Okay, what would you do if I did this?
好吧，如果我這樣你會怎麼做？